question if, for example, Vladivostok
вопрос если например э Владивосток
Khabarovsk Yes, for example, they will
Хабаровск Да объявят например там
potentially announce independence there Yes, how do you
потенциально о независимости Да как вы
residents of Nizhny Novgorod relate to this Hello Hello,
жители Нижнего Новгорода к этому
I’m from the
отнесёте Здравствуйте Здравствуйте я из
city of Khmelnitsky
города Хмельницкий Вы
Where are you from? I’m from Russia, the city of Nizhny Novgorod
откуда Я из России город Нижний Новгород
Nizhny Novgorod is what Gorky
Нижний Новгород это то что Горький
was called yes Yes, I understood everything correctly But
назывался да Да всё верно понял А вот
see What regions of Russia have you
смотрите В каких регионах России вы
been to
бывали
and the
а
republic maril city w Korola in Moscow
республика марил город ш Корола в Москве
Vladimir
Владимире
Tver in the Nizhny Novgorod region also that is, that is,
Твери по Нижегородской области ещ то
virtually everything is somewhere within
есть то есть фактически всё где-то в
close proximity from Nizhny
недалекой доступности от Нижнего
Novgorod So, well, Korola is 300 km from
Новгорода Так ну ж Корола она 300 км от
Nizhne 350 What is 300  km
Нижне 350 Это что такое 300 км
from
от
Europe is exactly what I wanted, that is, it turns out,
Европе как раз и хотел то есть
look, I’m a representative of a
получается смотрите я ээ представитель
research center, we’re dealing
исследовательского центра мы занимаемся
with
ээ
decentralization in the Russian Federation
децентрализация в Российской Федерации
Yes, and we’re studying how
Да и изучаем насколько
strong the connection between regions is, for example,
сильная связь между регионами например
this is what connects you with the Far East,
вот что вас связывает с дальним востоком
for example, here’s what connects you, a resident of Novgorod, with the
например вот вас жителя Новгорода с
Far East, well, personally
дальним востоком связывает ну лично меня
As a resident of nothing, commercial structures are
как жителя ничего коммерческие структуры
most likely connected if it’s a business or they
скорее всего связывают если это бизнес
can be connected there with
ни могут там связаны быть и с
Kazakhstan and that’s all yes Well, that is, it’s
Казахстаном и всё да Ну то есть это
trading Yes, but the question is if, for example,
торговать Да а вот вопрос если например
Vladivostok Khabarovsk Yes, for example, they will potentially announce
Владивосток Хабаровск Да объявят
independence there How do you residents of Nizhny
независимости Как вы жители Нижнего
Novgorod feel about this
Новгорода к этому
Well, personally, I don’t think so, but it
отнесёте ну лично я никак но на бюджете
goes without saying that it will affect the city’s budget. This will affect the
города само собой Это скажется на
budget of the lower city,
бюджете нижнего ного
say horses that have some kind of income
скаже кони которые имеют какие-то доходы
from these
с этих
regions. What kind of income? Yes, any business
регионов доходы Какие Да любой бизнес
can be located in Nizhny Novgorod,
может находиться в Нижнем Новгороде
receive money there from the Middle East.
получать деньги там из Ближнего Востока
Well, look at trading and  So
Ну так смотрите торговать и так смогут
companies can really Well, barriers will appear
компании же правда Ну так появятся
in the form of taxes of all sorts of levies,
барьеры в виде налогов всяких поборов
so now There are now There are
так сейчас Есть сейчас Есть
barriers Yes, in the form of taxes like those that
барьеры Да в виде налогов типа которые
Moscow collects taxes Yes,
забирает Москва налоги Да могут
other levies may appear in the form of taxes
появиться ещ другие поборы в виде пошли
because it turns out that you, as
изза того что получается что вы как
residents of Nizhny Novgorod, see that  if
жители Нижнего Новгорода видите что если
Vladivostok is disconnected you will feel
Владивосток отсоединиться Вам станет
worse of course, so And the question is, why do you need
хуже само собой так А вопрос А зачем вы
Vladivostok so Vladivostok can
Владивостоку так Владивосток может иметь
also have money from Nizhny Novgorod, it’s a city with a
также деньги с Нижне Новгорода это город
population of over a million, they can sell their
миллионник они там могут сбывать свой
goods there, their products, see
товар свою продукци е т смотри
Vladivo Novgorod and Nizhny Novgorod in
владиво Новгород и Нижний Новгород во
Vladivostok Yes, if Vladivostok is
Владивосток Да если Владивосток будет
independent  what is stopping them also, what
независимым что им мешает также что
will change in money, nothing will change Well, why will it become
изменится в деньгах ничего Ну почему
more expensive, what will become more expensive Well, there will be
дороже станет что станет дороже Ну
different customs duties, duties, as it exists between
различные как это существует между
different countries Look, the same thing, there is, for
разными странами Вот то же самое смотри
example, the European Union Yes, they are an
вот есть есть например Евросоюз Да они
independent state Yes, but they
независимые государство Да но
also united into an economic Union
объединились в экономический Союз также
Well  they can agree Yes, no taxes
Ну могут договориться Да никаких пошин
You have the Schengen zone, for example, you are right
Шенгенская зона у Вас например Вы правы
But it is necessary that they
Но это надо чтобы
agree will negotiate Well,
договорились будут договариваться Ну а в
what is the problem of
чём проблема
agreeing, look, they are agreeing
договориться смотри они договариваются
For what, yes in order for the
Для чего да
cooperation to be
для для того чтобы было сотрудничество
mutually beneficial if they have if you
взаимовыгодным если у них если у вас
now have mutually beneficial cooperation then
сейчас сотрудничество взаимовыгодное то
what  the problem of preserving it will be
в чём проблема его сохранить будет Ну
Well, look, the Soviet Union collapsed,
вот смотрите Советский Союз распался
many independent republics appeared,
появилось много республик
not all the republics
независимых не со всеми республиками
agreed on customs at the moment,
договорились о таможенном данный момен
that is, most likely the same thing can
то есть скорее всего тоже самое может
happen again if And why Why did
повториться если А почему Почему никто
n’t any of the republics want to join a customs
из республик не захотел в таможенный
union with Russia Because it’s economical for them  it
союз с Россией Потому что им это
’s not interesting, that’s
экономически неинтересно интерес вот А
why the republics weren’t interested in
почему республикам да не интересно было
joining an economic union with Russia.
с Россией вступать в экономический Союз
I don’t know. But for example, with Europe. It’s
Я не знаю А например с Европой
interesting. Why can Russia then
Интересно так Почему может Россия тогда
turn out to be Russia? Why is it that the
получается Россия прот для что
republics don’t benefit from economic
республикам не выгодно экономическое
cooperation with Russia? Well, I can’t
сотрудничество с Россией Ну я не могу за
answer for that.  I don’t get involved in these matters, I don’t
это отвечать я ж не лезу в эти дела я не
know all the subtleties, that is, look
знаю всех тонкостей то есть смотрите к
what I’m leading to Vladivostok there, for example
чему я веду Владивосток там например
Khabarovsk there The Far Eastern Republic is
хабарову там Дальневосточная республика
conditionally Yes, they are now economically connected
условно Да они экономически связанные
with China Japan there USA This is the
сейчас с Китаем Японией там США Вот это
Pacific region - this is the richest
Тихоокеанский регион - это богатейший
region on the planet yes South Korea Japan
регион планеты да Южная Корея Япония
China USA  there Damn, in my opinion, if I'm not
Китай США там е Блин по-моему если я не
mistaken, from Vladivostok to Australia
ошибаюсь от Владивостока в Австралию
will probably be closer than to Moscow yes yes
наверное будет ближе чем в Москву да да
So it turns out that the money of the world is
Так вот получается что деньги мира
somewhere there Well, also in Europe, there the
где-то вот там Ну ещё вот в Европе вот
money is there Technologies Why does
там Бабки там Технологии Зачем
Vladivostok need Nizhny Novgorod if it can
Владивостоку Нижний Новгород если можно
integrate  into this higher-priority
интегрироваться в эту более приоритетную
system Well, okay, what will Vladivostok
систему Ну хорошо а Владивосток что
offer to these countries
предложит этим странам
and what does it offer to
а что он предлагает
Moscow? Well, at the moment, from what
Москве Ну на данный момент из того что
can come to my mind, this is imported
мне в голову может прийти это импортные
cars, it’s not, it’s not that, it’s that they’re just in
автомобили не не так это это они просто
transit from it’s from Japan, but that’s
транзитом идут из это из Японии но это
quite big  business in the same
довольно Большой бизнес в том же
Vladivostok, see Vladivostok,
Владивостоке смотрите Владивосток
I'll give
дам
glory, there are natural resources, including
славо есть ресурсы природные в том числе
fossils and forests, sea, sea - This is a
там ископаемые и леса море море - Это
huge source of yes, seafood
огромный источник да э морепродуктов
that is imported here and to Moscow In
которые импортируются сюда и в Москву
short, to St. Petersburg and Wherever Where only they are
Короче и в Питер и Куда Куда только они
imported Yes, this is the port, this is, uh
импортируется Да Ээ это порт это ээ
let's say a trade gate Yes, this is the
скажем торговые ворота Да вот это
trade gate of the entire European and
торговые ворота всей европейской и
middle there near the Urals Yes, the gate there to the
средне там там у Урала Да ворота туда в
Pacific
Тихоокеанский
world, they can live quite happily
мир они могут жить довольно припеваючи
Yes, I don’t argue, most likely it
Да я не спорю могут скорее всего это
depends on the diplomatic missions how
зависит от дипломатических миссий как
all this will develop What
это всё будет развиваться Какие
priorities will be set by the locals there
приоритеты будут ставиться там местными
there by the heads of state there if they
там главами государства там если они
are formed. But for example, look also at
образуются А вот например смотрите тоже
this question.
такой вопрос
If we are still studying the possibility of
Если мы ещ изучаем возможность там
armed resistance there against the
вооружённого сопротивления против
Independence of the Republics, if these
Независимости Республик если эти
Republics there, Siberia, the Far East,
Республики там Сибирь Дальний Восток
declare independence just as the
провозгласят независимость так же как
Republics of the USSR left the
Республики СССР вышли из состава
Soviet Union and here you are,
Советского Союза и вот вы жители
for example, residents of Nizhny Novgorod  Novgorod, uh, they would like to
например Нижнего Новгорода ээ хотели бы
return them by force by force to
их вернуть насильно вооружённым
Russia, so it does not depend
путём в состав России так это зависит не
on the residents, but on the priorities of the heads of
от жителей А от приоритетов глав
state, of course they want the head of
государств само собой они хотят глава
state of the Russian Federation. If he
государстве Российской Федерации Если
tells us that we need to return Vladivostok by
скажет нам нужно вернуть Владивосток
military means, will you, as a resident of Nizhny
военным путём вы как житель Нижнего
Novgorod, support this
Новгорода будете поддерживать Это
decision or
решение или
not?  I won’t tell you right away, I understand,
нет Я вам так сходу не скажу понял
okay, let’s go, are you ready to fight
хорошо давайте так готовы ли вы воевать
for the Far East against the people who
за Дальний Восток против людей которые
will declare independence there personally, you do
объявят независимость там лично вы это
n’t depend on the citizens Personally, I would
зависит не от граждан Лично я ни на
n’t go to any front because I
какой фронт не пошёл бы потому что я
choose to live, I have one life and  I
выбираю жить вот у меня одна жизнь и я
want to live my life, I think that this is what
хочу жить свою жизни я думаю что так
all people on Earth in any country want,
хотят все люди на Земле в любой стране
but most likely the
но скорее всего для
state needs these lands there from the
государства эти земли нужны там с точки
point of view of defense because there is access
зрения обороны потому что там есть выход
to the sea, there is another continental part,
к морю там другая материковая часть
strategically these lands are important and
стратегически эти земли Важны и само
the state itself is not  wants to
собой государство не захочет эти земли
give up these lands because go figure, the
отдавать потому что поди Государство -
State is who the State is people, it’s not
это кто Государство - это люди это же не
some kind of planet or alien, for
какой-то из планеты и инопланетной вот
example, look, there are two
например смотри есть два кандидата в
presidential candidates. Yes, one will say, I will
президенты Да один будет говорить так я
return the Far East to Russia by military means,
верну военным путём Дальний Восток в
and the second says  I recognize the
состав России а второй говорит я признаю
Far East and their Independence and
Дальний Восток и ихнюю Независимость и
let them live, you would vote for which one
пусть они живут вы бы за какого
of them
проголосовали из них
Well, well, depending on what the leader of
Ну Ну смотря что скажет руководитель
this country says if he justifies it, how
этой страны если он это обоснуете как
we need it for abc not not your
это нам нужно для абц не не вашей вашей
Russia, for example, look, the Far
России например смотрите вот Дальний
East declared independence, all of
Восток провозгласил независимость всё
them  are already starting to live Regardless, so
они уже начинают жить Независимо так и у
you have two presidential candidates, and
вас есть два кандидата в президенты да
for example,
например
there are only two left and one says
осталось только двое и один говорит
vote for me. I have mobilized everyone and we will
голосуйте за меня Я мобили зру всех и мы
return the Far East to the
вернём военным путём Дальний Восток в
Russian Federation by military means. The second one
состав Российской Федерации второй
says I recognize the independence
говорит я признаю независимость
of Vladivostok. Let them live once.  they
Владивостока Да пусть они живут раз они
decided so and for whom you will vote
так решили да за кого вы проголосует
Well, depending on how it will affect my life there
Ну смотря как это на моей жизни скажется
should be arguments of the first and second
должны быть аргументы первого и второго
Well, they say they say One says
Ну вот они говорят говорят Один говорит
that they chose this way Yes, we should not
что они так выбрали Да мы не должны
lose the lives of our Russians Yes,
терять жизни наших россиян Да
Nizhny Novgorod residents so that they die
нижегородцев для того чтобы они умирали
against the residents  Vladivostok, yes, since they are
против жителей Владивостока да раз они
good, if he says, I won’t
хорошо если он скажет я не буду никого
mobilize anyone. Let them separate, but in
мобилизовать Пусть они отделяются но При
this situation, your income there will fall by
таком раскладе ваши доходы там упадут в
half and you will become poorer. Most likely,
два раза и вы станете беднее Скорее
I won’t vote for him. Yeah, I
всего я за него не проголосую
understand, that is, you vote for the one
Угу понял то есть вы проголосуйте за
who says, look for  so
того который говорит смотрите для того
that your income does not fall Yes, you will need to
чтобы ваши доходы не упали Да нужно
throw 100,000 Russian
будет взять кинуть 100000 российских
men to seize Vladivostok
мужиков на захват Владивостока
Yes, what 100,000 men if
Да какие 100.000 мужиков если
this is if these are specially trained people
это если это специально обученные люди у
whose work involves being specially
кого работа подразумевает специально
trained, by this moment everyone will have
обученные до этого момента уже все
died in Ukraine, there will be
сдохнут в Украине это уже специально
no specially trained people left anymore  you have
обученных не останется уже же у вас там
mobilization there Why did they do it because the
мобилизацию Почему делали потому что
specially trained ones went somewhere the
специально обученные куда-то делись дани
tributes from the scientists will end, yes, that is, who
с во ученые закончатся да то есть кто
will
будет
fight? As a civil revolutionary, I don’t
воевать Я как гражданской революцион не
want to fight, yes, that is, look, it
хочу воевать вот да то есть смотрите
turns out again, let’s One say
получается ещё раз давайте Один говорит
Yes, we Recognize the independence
Да мы Признаем независимость
of Vladivostok Yes, but  temporarily your income
Владивостока Да но временно ваши доходы
Yes will decrease a little because yes we
Да немножко снизятся потому что да мы не
will not take from the Far East
будем с Дальнего Востока забирать
the resources that we took Previously Yes and the
ресурсы которые мы забирали Раньше Да а
second one says look So let’s make
второй говорит смотрите Так давайте так
sure your income does not decrease so we
чтобы ваши доходы не снижались так нам
need to gather an army and take back the
нужно собрать армию и захватить назад
Far East in order to continue to take
Дальний Восток чтобы забирать дальше
resources from them  who
ресурсы с них вы за кого
will you vote for in case I won’t vote
проголосует случае голосовать не буду
Damn That is, without you they will elect a president
Блин То есть без вас выберут президента
like this Because in both the first and second
так Потому что и в первом и во втором
options there are bad
варианте есть плохие
moments Well, yes, but from the two zones you need to
моменты Ну да но из двух зон нужно
choose one less Well
выбрать какое-то меньше
Well, this is the same as if now there are
Ну Ну это тоже самое что если сейчас
citizens of Ukraine  They’ll probably ask you,
граждан Украины спросят Вам наверное
you’re tired of the war, you want to live everything, we
война надоела Вы ведь все жить хотите
give it to the republic and don’t fight, or
что отдаём республике и не воюем или
mobilize and fight and take it away. But
мобилизует и воюем и забираем вот А
look, in Ukraine, in Ukraine there’s no
смотрите в Украине в Украине вообще не
such question at all, because
стоит такой вопрос потому что из Украины
no one from Ukraine is separating from Ukraine;
никто не отделяется на Украину напало
another state attacked, that’s a completely different
другое государство тут совсем другой
question  Yes, for example, if not, look if
вопрос Да например если нет смотри если
China attacked you and took
бы на вас напал Китай и забрал
Vladivostok, then it would be an analogy with
Владивосток тогда бы это было аналогия с
Ukraine But here it’s not like that. I’m telling you. For
Украиной А тут не так Я же говорю Вот
example, by the
например
democratic process, yes, yes, then the
демократическим процессом да да даль
East declares independence.
Восток провозглашает независимость Да
Yes, Russia is left with two two candidates. You’re
вот Россия остаётся два два кандидата Вы
good. You’re not.  go to the polls, don’t
хорошо Вы не не идёте на выборы не
vote, but which one would be better for you,
голосуйте Но какой бы вы для вас лучше
so that the one who wins is the one who
было чтобы какой победил тот который
said that we are ready to recognize
сказал что мы готовы признать
independence and continue to live in goodness and
независимость Да и жить дальше в добре и
neighborliness, or the one who says we will take
соседстве да либо тот который скажет мы
military means, let us
военным путём Да
seize this Far
захватим этот Дальний
East Well,
Восток
I, I say, I  I wouldn’t go to the front, but
Ну я я говорю я не пошёл бы на фронт но
I understand perfectly well 100% that there will be
я прекрасно понимаю 100% что будет
mobilization and they will return these lands.
мобилизация и будут возвращать эти земли
I don’t know a single country where people would
Я не знаю ни одной страны где люди
declare their independence and the
провозгласили бы свою независимость и
state would deal with it, we are like that. Yes, for
государство мерило бы с этим мы такое Да
God’s sake, [ __ ], look, there aren’t a lot of
ради Бога Бля посмотри не куча есть
countries that are like this  in the 20th century, a large
стран которые вот в XX веке большое
number of countries declared
количество стран провозгласила
independence
независимость
from Britain. Yes, and without problems, they live
от Британии Да и без проблем да живут
together
дружно
now, so it could not economically
сейчас так она экономически не могла
support Britain after the war, that
поддерживать э Британия после войны то
is, once again, economically, Britain
есть ещё раз экономически Британия не
could not support, for example,
могла там например
some of its small colonies
какие-то свои колонии маленькие
that now live from
поддерживать которые сейчас живут из
Britain  they could have lived even richer,
Британии они може жили даже богаче
for example.
например
So here’s the situation: Britain
Так тут ситуация в чём вот у Британии
used to have colonies, now there
раньше были колонии сейчас на этих же
are factories on the same lands. Since then, they
землях остались заводы С тех врем они
still bring income to Britain. It’s
по-прежнему приносят доход Британии
just that now it’s not a colony of Britain, and
Просто теперь это не колония Британии и
that means there’s less responsibility.
то есть меньше ответственности
If before it was  the colony
получается Если раньше это была колония
and Britain were conditionally responsible
и Британия условно несла ответственность
for the population that was there then now
за население которое там было то сейчас
Britain is not responsible something something
Британия ответственность не несёт что-то
You’re not just some kind of fable in
что-то Ты не это уже какие-то басни
short there And that’s all yes Well why Look at the
короче там И всё да Ну почему Посмотрите
former colonies of Britain
колонии Британии бывшие
Look we’ll take it let’s say
Посмотрите мы мы возьмём давай так
how much you  you said the thesis that there
сколько ты ты сказал тезис что ни одной
is not a single country that would be
страны нету такой чтобы добровольно ей
given independence voluntarily, like yes, a bunch of countries in
отдали независимость типа да куча стран
Africa Look at most countries in
Африку Посмотрите большинство стран
Africa Yes, they were not independent at the
Африки Да они не были независимыми в в
beginning of the 20th century Yes, what gave them
начале XX века Да что дали им
independence Ida they cooperate now
независимость Ида сотрудничают сейчас
as equals, what is the problem Yes, how
как с равными в чём проблема Да как
they cooperate  look that in Africa that in
сотрудничают посмотрите что в Африке что
Africa there are
в Африке в Африке есть компании по
oil production companies, conditionally, while the people are
добыче нефти условно при этом народ
poor and no one with this that there are
бедный и никто с этим что что компании
oil production companies did not understand what is
по добычи нефти есть не понял что
wrong with the production companies
плохого в компаниях по добы
but they also pump out resources from there they
но они выкачивают также оттуда ресурсы
sell them they earn money Look no
продают их зарабатывают они Смотри не
Yes, they make money, they bring
есть Да они зарабатывают они приносят
technology there, Yes, the local government
туда технологии Да местная власть
sets certain taxes, Yes,
устанавливает налоги определённые Да
fees for this for the use of subsoil, and
пошлины за это за использование недр И
so on. Yes, it
так дальше Да оно
gets it, so there is a government there that is loyal to the
получает так там стоит власть лояльная
countries. So, that is, a conditionally French
странам Вот то есть условно французская
company that produces oil in Africa,
компания которая добывает нефть в Африке
in Africa, this country costs Well  that is, in the
в Африке этой стране стоит Ну то есть в
state administration there is a president
государстве управлении стоит президент
who is loyal to this France and to France
который лоялен этой Франции и Францию
in general who who puts this
вообще кто кто ставит этого
president Well, obviously not the People but who Well
президента Ну явно не Народ а кто Ну
because I see how people live there
потому что я вижу как там люди живут
Wait a minute and who who who puts the president
Подожди а кто кто кто ставит президента
Well someone is lobbying for all these things So
Ну кто-то лоббирует все эти вещи Так
stop question: Who installs the president in the
стоп вопрос А кто ставит президента в
Russian
Российской
Federation?
Федерации
How to understand who installs Well, you
Как понять кто ставит Ну ктото вы же
said in Africa, someone installs the president
сказали в Африке кто-то ставит президент
and not the people, so I ask similarly:
а не народ вот я Аналогично спрашиваю А
Who installs the president then in the Russian
кто ставит президента тогда в Российской
Federation? I can’t answer that for you.
Федерации я вам не могу на это ответить
I don’t know him.  put And who puts it, well,
Я его не ставил А кто ставит ну и вы так
wait, you didn’t put this uh in
подожди вы и не ставили этого ээ в
Africa as a president, but here you answer something very
Африке президента но тут что-то очень
clearly about Africa that it’s not the
чётко отвечаете про Африку что это не
people who choose it, someone puts it there And
народ выбирает его кто-то ставит там А
then who puts it because I see
кто же тогда ставит потому что я вижу
news from  In Africa, I see that people live
новости из Африки я вижу что люди живут
poor, no one likes this life, but
бедные никому эта жизнь не нравится но
at the same time the government there does not change and
при этом там правительство не меняется и
European companies continue to pump
европейские компании продолжают качать
there, no question, see the question
там не вопрос смотрите вопрос
Russia lives
Россия живёт
poorly if we look in comparison with
бедно если мы посмотрим в сравнении с
Europe and America, it lives poorly and the
Европой и Америкой она живёт бедно и
government there does not change Russia  does not
правительство там не меняется Россия не
live in poverty Russia lives exactly
живёт бедно Россия живёт ровно
in the middle of the economic Russia lives in
посередине экономического Россия живёт
poverty Russia lives in
бедно Россия жит
trouble Moscow yes you you Nizhny Novgorod Yes
бед Москву да ты ты Нижнего Новгорода Да
you have been to the villages of the Nizhny Novgorod
ты был в деревнях Нижегородской
region and in Nizhny Novgorod Yes you have been and the
области а в нижегород Да был да там
standard of living there is very different from
сильно отличается уровень жизни от
Africa from Africa Yes I can’t say I
Африки от Африки Да я не могу сказать я
haven’t been  in Africa Well, if you compare in
не был в Африке Ну если сравнивать в
terms of the fact that people don’t live on the street, they
плане того что люди не живут на улице у
have their own houses, they clearly
них есть свои дома у них есть ясно и в
have houses in Africa. But heating, look
Африке есть дома А вот отопление смотри
how many houses are gasified in the Nizhny Novgorod
сколько газифицирован в Нижегородской
region,
области домов
the problem is Yes,
проблема Да
private
частных
private private house, it depends
частных частный дом это зависит
solely on the person who owns it
исключительно человека который владеет
you see That is, when blacks are blacks
видишь То есть когда [__] [__]
Africans They have a kind of problem Yes, they
африканцы У них типа проблема Да вот они
live there poorly And in the Nizhny Novgorod
там бедно живут А в Нижегородской
region it all depends on the person,
области это всё человека зависит
listen Well, if you conditionally
слушайте Ну если вам условно вашу
get centralized gas in your village and
деревню заводят газ централизованный и
you don’t connect to it, who’s to blame for this, the
вы не подключаетесь к нему кто в этом
keys to gas in the village  Nizhny Novgorod
вино лючи к газу в деревне Нижегородской
region Well, I know that the prices were from
области Ну я знаю что расценки были от
70 to 120,000 rubles to 12, that is, like a mini,
70 до 120.000 руб до 12 то есть как мини
about a thousand dollars Well, yes, and I
порядка типа тысячи долларов Ну да и я
heard more prices, I heard more
больше слышал расценки я больше слышал
prices, so yes Question question uh,
расценки так вот да Вопрос вопрос
people in the village of the Nizhny Novgorod
ээ у людей в деревне Нижегородской
region have 1,000 dollars here  so howl
области есть 1.000 долларов вот так выть
even more than a thousand it turns out, it’s
даже больше тысячи это получается это же
also at the prices that were then the
ещё по ценам те которые были тогда
dollar was about 1.00 2.000 a
доллар был это порядка где-то 1.00 2.000
person in the Nizhny Novgorod region
будет у человека в Нижегородской области
in the village will have so much money Well, that means you need to
в деревне столько денег Ну значит надо
save it up, it’s economically profitable because
накопить это экономически выгодно потому
that means people in Africa  they live
что то есть значит в Африке люди живут
poorly And in the Nizhny Novgorod region
бедно А в Нижегородской области просто
they just need to save up, for some reason they haven’t
им надо накопить они почему-то не
saved up If you take the
накопили Если вы возьмёте индекс
economic index, where did you run off to
экономического раз куда
Hello Ukra, how is it
убежал Привет Укра как он бешка
short
короче
No, this is a very cool video, subscribe Like
Нет это очень классный ролик подпишитесь
Leave a comment and
Поставьте лайк Оставьте коммент да ещё
again, give us fresh conclusions uh Vladivostok
раз давайте свежие выводы ээ Владивосток
Yes we need  to a guy from Nizhny Novgorod so that
Да нужен парню из Нижнего Новгорода чтоб
he doesn’t lose money, yes, that is, he
он не потерял бабки да то есть он
looks at Vladivostok as a
смотрит на Владивосток как на
potential resource, this whole
потенциальный ресурс вот вся эта
Central Russia and so on. She
Центральная Россия и так дальше Она
looks at everything beyond the Urals, you know
смотрит на всё что за Уралом знаете как
how you can get money and resources from here,
то откуда можно тащить бабки и ресурсы
it’s all on Eva  just we saw
вот это всё вот на Еву прям мы видели
subscribe to th Telegram right now
подпишись на й Telegram прям зараз
onk more and more
онк дуже и дуже
respectfully
важливо